Emily Necciai Mayeski

Technical Writer & Instructional Designer

I treat documentation and learning resources like a product - as if a purchase decision depends on a user's experience with it. I want to go where I can envision and implement beautiful enablement experiences for SaaS products and integrations.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

CyberCube Analytics, Inc., Remote/New York, NY
Lead Technical Writer on the Product & Analytics Team
January 2020 - PRESENT

- Launched and currently manages our CMS/Online Documentation site, our LMS/Internal Learning systems, and all internal documentation on Confluence and Google Docs. Also set up and manages a content request system for these resources.
- Writes and manages all online product user documentation content (user guides, API specs) and site via Strapi CMS.
- Writes and designs all PDF and print documentation, including for our model methodology and change management guides.
- Creates and edits internal and external learning aids (videos and learning courses) for CyberCube Academy and YouCube.
- Works with Product Managers, analysts, UX designers, researchers/SMEs, and Developers throughout sprints to research and rapidly build documentation and supporting resources (videos, gifs, etc.).

Braze, Inc., New York, NY

Technical Writer/Instructional Designer & Documentation Manager on Customer Education Team

March 2018 - January 2020

- Designed and managed processes the product/feature design process for the Braze Documentation site (including full site redesign and all additional features like Landing Pages, glossaries, and other templates), including management of the Braze Docs Github repo.
- Collected and acted on data for content decisions from Google Analytics, Looker, and other platforms.
- Works with Engineers, Onboarding and Success Managers, Support and more to research, write and revise sections, pages, templates and other articles to build an internal and customer-facing knowledge base, including API, SDK, and partner integration documentation.

SocialCode, LLC, New York, NY

Technical Writer/Instructional Designer on Learning & Development/Training Team September 2016 - March 2018

 Created and managed onboarding paths, trainers, courses, and curriculum for social and digital ad management, as well as employees.

Management Science Associates, Inc., Pittsburgh, PA Technical Writer/Instructional Designer June 2015 - September 2016

 Constructed and standardized technical and user-friendly documentation and training materials for data software programs and apps. 724.322.9655
enmayeski@gmail.com
Emily-necciai.squarespace.com
www.linkedin.com/in/emilynecciai/

SKILLS

Role-Based

Needs Analysis

Curriculum/Program

Design & Management

Technical

Digital and Print Media

Management & Review

UX Copy & Docs Site

Design

LMS Management

Product Management

Agile Processes

TECHNOLOGY

Languages

HTML

CSS & Advanced CSS

Javascript

OpenAPI

Markdown

Git

Docs/Knowledge

Infrastructures

Github Repo

StrapiCMS

Algolia Search

Hubspot

SharePoint

JIRA

Confluence

Learning Management

Systems

Exceed LMS

NorthpassLMS

Blackboard

Content Creation

Articulate Suite

Adobe Suite

Camtasia

Emily Necciai Mayeski

Technical Writer & Instructional Designer Continued...

EDUCATION

Master of Arts in English (Literary & Cultural Studies)

Carnegie-Mellon University

Graduated May 2015 - GPA 3.78 - Pittsburgh, PA

Primary Projects

Post-War Women's Fashion, 18th Century Soldiers and Law, Dickens' Serial Novels, Superman and the Anthropocene

Bachelor of Arts in English (Concentration in Professional Writing)

Washington & Jefferson College

Graduated May 2014 - GPA 3.64 - Washington, PA

Primary Projects

Editor-In-Chief of the Wooden Tooth Review, Layout Editor of the Pandora Yearbook, Writer for the Red & Black Newspaper, Tim O'Brien's Realistic Non-Fiction War Stories

Continued Learning

Full Stack Development Bootcamp

George Washington University

May 2021 - October 2021

Product Management

General Assembly Online

December 2017 - New York, NY

Primary Project

Design a product plan for a small business Learning Management System.

NOTABLE PROJECTS

YouCube Internal LMS Purchase and Launch

User Documentation Site Launch (April 2020)

Lead and managed the purchase, set up, and support for CyberCube's new collaborative learning initiative - an LMS (Northpass) meant to allow any employee to create their own content and share with the company. Planning to create a customer-facing LMS soon, too.

CyberCube Online Docs Launch

User Documentation Site Launch (April 2020)

Planned, led, and assisted the design of the gated online documentation site for CyberCube's cross-product documentation, as well as launched the public documentation site for CyberCube's "Login Help" documentation on Hubspot.

Project Mallard

Braze Documentation Site Revamp (October 2018)

Planned and led the redesign and re-architecture of the Braze Documentation site to be more direct in it's audience, purpose, mission, values, and more (including creating Style, Formatting, and Contribution Guides). A later project involved preparing and launching the associated repo as Open Source.